Jascha Ostholt

frontend developer



details

Contact

@: jascha.ostholt@gmail.com

P: <u>+49 176 / 47</u>6 467 99

Li: <u>linkedin.com/in/jascha-</u>ostholt/

Location

Berlin & remote

languages

German English Native Fluent

stack

Nuxt, Vue, Typescript, Tailwind, Anime.js

skills

Agile Project Management, Product Management, Stakeholder Management, Leading Workshops

summary

I'm a passionate frontend developer with 6+ years of experience in development and agile team leadership.

I balance pragmatism with attention to detail and writing clean and future proof code.

I like to take responsibility and leaving my professional comfort zone. I care about my work environment and smart design.

experience

2020 - Today

Web Developer & Product Owner elvah GmbH | elvah.de

- leading a diverse, cross-functional team of 10-12 people for one of germanys fastest growing mobility startups
- created landing pages, <u>registration flow</u> and account management
- actively leading and mentoring the web developers of my team

- doubled conversion rate by updating website and registration flow
- Improved elvah's search engine visibility by over 300% by building a glossary
- created a shared component library for elvah's web projects
- Stack: Nuxt 2&3, Vue, Typescript, Anime.js

2016 - 2019 Software Developer kreait GmbH agency

- led a product team extending a company CI and website
- developed a SaaS Slack bot for supporting agile teams with their stand-ups that was used by over 400 companies
- designed and developed a microservices architecture for the Slack bot
- took part in the development of various apps and services. From small MVPs, timeframed to prove or unprove a business hypothesis in one month, to large scale microservice architectures with hundreds of thousands of users
- had the opportunity to work with brands like UEFA, Sport1, Melitta, iFolor and Positec
- Stack: Nuxt, Vue, Typescript, Kotlin, Java, Spring, AWS

2018 - Today Software Developer / Designer Freelance

- advised <u>Peter Lenné School</u> in updating their web presence
- created a portfolio website for the artist <u>Dominik</u> <u>Galleya</u>
- developed UX concepts for various artist and built small business pages

education

2022	Certified Scrum Product Owner
	scrum.org profile
2015 - 2019	Applied Computer Science
	HTW Berlin
Grades	Overall: 1.7
	Thesis: 1.3
	Colloquium: 1.0
Focus	Machine Learning, Data Science